https://www.centrastate.com/policies-and-procedures/

skip to main content search
Search
Header Search
Recent Searches Clear Searches Quick LinksNewsBlogInsuranceCareersVolunteerFamily Medicine Residency Program
Policies and Procedures
Policies and Proceduresmriker2020-07-15T14:58:18-04:00A list of policies can be found below. These include HIPAA Privacy Policy, Corporate Compliance, Notice of Non-Discrimination, NJ Out-of-Network Consumer Protection Act, Patient Rights, Social Media Policy, Website Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.HIPPA Privacy PracticesThis notice describes how medical information about you that is maintained by CentraState Healthcare System or any of its member facilities may be used and disclosed, and how you can get access to this information.HIPAA Privacy PolicyCorporate ComplianceCentraState Healthcare System is dedicated to conducting business lawfully and ethically; thus, we invite anyone who is aware of any violation, question, incident or situation to report it via our hotline or website.There will be no adverse action or retribution against anyone for reporting a suspected violation or irregularity. Such reporting is protected by both federal and state laws, as well as CentraState policy.Corporate ComplianceNotice of Non-DiscriminationCentraState Healthcare System complies with applicable Federal civil rights laws and does not discriminate on the basis of race, color, national origin, age, disability, or sex.  CentraState Healthcare System does not exclude people or treat them differently because of race, color, national origin, age, disability, or sex.Notice of Non-DiscriminationNJ Out-of-Network Consumer Protection ActCentraState is dedicated to providing consumers with as much information as possible regarding potential healthcare costs. This law has been passed to reform healthcare insurance by enhancing consumer protections against certain surprise out-of-network bills. The law also aims to create a system to resolve certain healthcare billing disputes, contain rising costs, and measure success with respect to these goals. Accordingly, we have listed information on the insurers and products the hospital participates in as well as any exceptions.NJ Out-of-Network Consumer Protection ActPatient RightsView your rights as a patient of CentraState Medical Center.Patient RightsSocial Media PolicyCentraState Healthcare System welcomes active communication including discussions, commentary, and questions, but we ask that you keep your comments and posts relevant and respectful. View our social media policy.Social Media PolicyWebsite Privacy PolicyCentraState Healthcare System, including its affiliates CentraState Medical Center, The Manor Health and Rehabilitation, Monmouth Crossing, Family Practice of CentraState, CentraState Family Medicine Residency Program, CentraState Healthcare Partners, respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.Website Privacy PolicyTerms of UsePlease read this agreement entirely and carefully before accessing this website. By accessing the site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions on the link below, which are intended to be fully effective and binding upon all users.Terms of Use
Keep updated with the latest
